因此，生命大约在36亿年前出现在地球上。但对于大部分
So life appeared on planet earth about 3.6 billion years ago. But for the bulk of that
时间，生物，地球上的生命，是无法看到的。大约5亿年前
time, organisms, life on the planet, was not able to see. Around 500 million years ago
生命技术发生了革命，出现了视觉感受
there was a revolution in the technology of life and the sense of vision appeared, and
它在许多物种中出现得很快，并且导致了它的多样性
it appeared very quickly across a number of species and it led to a great diversity in
生活的方式。所以此时此前5亿年前堪称寒武纪爆发
the forms of life. So at this point 500 million years ago called the Cambrian explosion when
突然间，所有这些视觉启用的生命形式开始在地球上漫游。
suddenly all these vision-enabled life forms started to roam the planet.
这些生命形式中最早也许是最成功的一种是三叶虫，和
One of the earliest and perhaps most successful of those life forms is the trilobite, and
在这里，我有一个化石三叶虫。他们在百万年前出现了500件事并且他们住了
here I have a fossilised trilobite. They appeared 500 something million years ago and they lived
这个星球上有2.7亿年的历史。因此它们是具有分段的动物
on the planet for something like 270 million years. So they are an animal with a segmented
身体和他们有两个相当原始的，按现代标准，复眼。而且感觉
body and they had two fairly primitive, by modern standards, compound eyes. And the sense
视力使动物具有竞争优势。如果动物可能会看到另一只动物
of vision gave animals a competitive advantage. If an animal could see another animal, perhaps
它是一种狩猎动物，它想捕食其他动物，如果它有一种感觉
it was a hunting animal and it wanted to prey on that other animal, if it had a sense of
愿景它有一个真正的优势，它不仅仅是盲目地碰到它。他可以
vision it had a real advantage, it didn’t just have to blindly bump into it. He can
实际上看到那只动物在哪里并追踪并消耗它。如果你是这样的话
actually see where that animal is and go after it and consume it. And similarly if you were
一种猎物，一种有人可能想要吃的动物，如果你有意识的话
a prey animal, the sort of animal that someone might want to eat, then if you had a sense
视力和你有眼睛，然后你可以感觉到一个捕食者来了，你可以采取
of vision and you had eyes then you could sense a predator coming and you could take
一些回避行动。因此，视野导致了......几乎是地球上的军备竞赛作为掠夺者
some evasive action. So vision led to this… almost an arms race on planet earth as predators
和猎物动物获得视觉，他们改善了视觉，直到
and prey animals gain the sense of vision and they improved the sense of vision until
我们今天在非常非常多的动物身上拥有非常复杂的视野。
we have the sort of very sophisticated vision in very, very many animals today.
因此，大约5.4亿年前，地球上出现了视觉感。什么时候
So the sense of vision appeared on planet earth about 540 million years ago. And when
它似乎改变了游戏规则。事实上，视觉感觉非常有效，
it appeared it was a game changer. In fact, the sense of vision was so effective that,
随着时间的推移，十种不同类型的眼睛设计已经发展。例如，透镜的眼睛
over time, ten different sorts of eye designs have evolved. For instance, the lensed eye
我们有，昆虫有复眼，奇怪的反射器为基础的眼睛
that we have, the compound eye that a insect has, the strange reflector based eyes that
扇贝有等等。因此，这个星球上有十种不同的眼睛设计。和
scallops have and so on. So there are ten different designs of eyes on the planet. And
事实上，与我们所拥有的一样，透镜的眼睛已被发明七次
the lensed eye, like the one we have, has, in fact, been invented seven times across
不同的动物物种和时间。所以对我来说，这些事实认为愿景是
different animal species and across time. So to me these facts argue that vision is
一种非常重要且真正有效的方式来感知周围世界正在发生的事情
a really important and really effective way of sensing what is going on in the world around
您。当然，视力需要依旧点亮
you. Now of course vision needs light in order
为了操作，我们需要用环境光照亮场景。光子反射自
to operate, we need the scene to be illuminated with ambient light. Photons reflected from
进入我们眼睛的场景，它们落在视网膜上并产生一些神经刺激。绝对
the scene into our eyes, they fall on the retina and create some neural stimulus. Absolutely
必须有光源，但当然我们已经在一个真正的行星上进化了
has to have a source of light, but of course we have evolved on a planet next to a really
明亮的星星。所以光线充足。这是一个非常合理的解决方案。
bright star. So light is in abundance. It is a very logical solution to the problem.
我们拥有丰富的光源，我们已经发展了许多传感器
We have an abundant source of light and we have evolved the sensor which has got many
优点，但主要是能够感知超出我们的距离正在发生的事情
advantages, but primarily the ability to sense what is going on at a distance beyond our
指尖。那么视觉感是如何演变的呢？那里
fingertips. So how did the sense of vision evolve? There
对此有很多猜测，但一般认为是光敏细胞
is a lot of speculation about this, but generally it is accepted that light sensitive cells
很久以前出现在非常原始的生命形体上，超过500万
appeared on the bodies of very primitive life forms a long time ago, more than 500 million
几年前，他们有能力感知亮度或光线。也许这就是
years ago, and they have the ability to sense brightness or light. And perhaps this was
有用的解决方向是什么，以及哪种方式下降，也许你可以看到阴影
useful to work out which way was up and which way was down and maybe you could see the shadow
经历的事情，这是一个有用的东西。所以这些光感受器可以
of something going across and that was a useful thing to have. So these photoreceptors could
感觉光，它们通过某种原始神经纤维连接到某种程度
sense light and they were connected by some sort of primitive nerve fibres to some sort
原始大脑。这显然是一个有用的想法，因为结束
of primitive brain. This was clearly a useful idea because over
光感受器被安排成曲线或三维的时间进入杯子。
time the photoreceptors were arranged into a curve, or in three dimensions, into a cup.
这使得光感受器能够响应来自特定方向的光线
And this allowed the photoreceptors to respond to rays that came from a particular direction
在太空。这比仅知道有一些亮点更有用
in space. And this was more useful than just knowing that there was something bright out
在那里，现在我们知道了明亮事物的方向，这带来了一些优势。这个
there, now we knew the direction of the bright thing and this conferred some advantage. This
随着时间的推移，设计得到了提升，房间里充满了水，也许是他们的
design was refined over time, the chamber became filled with water, perhaps they had
更好的光学性能，然后有一些覆盖物进化。然后是镜头
better optical properties, and then there was sort of coverings evolved. And then lenses
进化。直到我们今天得到类似人眼的东西，我们才有，保护
evolved. Until we get to something like the human eye today were we have, you know, protective
层，我们有镜头。我们有一个虹膜，它调节光量
layers, and we have lenses. We have an iris, which regulates the amount of light which
落在视网膜上。因此，我们可以在低光照和强光条件下良好地运行。
falls onto the retinas. So we can operate quite well in low light and bright light conditions.
这里显示的这个黄色层的感光器通过一束连接
The photoreceptors, which are this yellow layer shown here, are connected by a bunch
神经纤维，视神经，将这些刺激带到光学或视觉部分
of nerve fibres, the optic nerve, which carry those stimuli to the optical or visual parts
大脑这实际上是位于我们脑后的大脑的一部分。
of the brain. And that is actually the part of the brain located at the back of our head.